<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Taiwan &#8211; Hello Wellcome To Us</title>
	<atom:link href="https://secure.sbam.org/tag/taiwan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://secure.sbam.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 18:06:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Chinese aircraft carrier in the Taiwan Strait</title>
		<link>https://secure.sbam.org/chinese-aircraft-carrier-in-the-taiwan-strait/</link>
					<comments>https://secure.sbam.org/chinese-aircraft-carrier-in-the-taiwan-strait/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tetreamra]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 18:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air force]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China and Taiwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taiwan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://secure.sbam.org/?p=26</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China&#8217;s aircraft carrier Shandong was spotted in the Taiwan Strait. Shandong crossed the Taiwan Strait on Saturday. At that time there were two other ships with it. The Ministry of Defense of Taiwan announced this information today. Taiwan&#8217;s Ministry of Defense says the aircraft carrier Shandong, which joined China&#8217;s military in 2019, was heading north...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China&#8217;s aircraft carrier Shandong was spotted in the Taiwan Strait. Shandong crossed the Taiwan Strait on Saturday. At that time there were two other ships with it. The Ministry of Defense of Taiwan announced this information today.</p>
<p>Taiwan&#8217;s Ministry of Defense says the aircraft carrier Shandong, which joined China&#8217;s military in 2019, was heading north through the Taiwan Strait on Saturday afternoon. At that time it was on the border between the two countries.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Defense said that the passage of the Chinese aircraft carrier with two ships through the Taiwan Strait is closely monitored and they have responded appropriately.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Defense of China was contacted to inquire about the matter, but there was no response. There was no mention of it on the social media channels of China&#8217;s armed forces.</p>
<p>The aircraft carrier Shandong also took part in China&#8217;s military exercises around Taiwan last month.</p>
<p>Earlier in March last year, the Shandong crossed the Taiwan Strait a few hours before the talks between the President of China and the United States.</p>
<p>China has recently increased military activity around Taiwan. The self-governing island of Taiwan has also objected to this. However, Beijing considers Taiwan to be an integral part of China.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://secure.sbam.org/chinese-aircraft-carrier-in-the-taiwan-strait/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
