<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; Hello Wellcome To Us</title>
	<atom:link href="https://secure.sbam.org/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://secure.sbam.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 18:06:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Chinese aircraft carrier in the Taiwan Strait</title>
		<link>https://secure.sbam.org/chinese-aircraft-carrier-in-the-taiwan-strait/</link>
					<comments>https://secure.sbam.org/chinese-aircraft-carrier-in-the-taiwan-strait/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tetreamra]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 18:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air force]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China and Taiwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taiwan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://secure.sbam.org/?p=26</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China&#8217;s aircraft carrier Shandong was spotted in the Taiwan Strait. Shandong crossed the Taiwan Strait on Saturday. At that time there were two other ships with it. The Ministry of Defense of Taiwan announced this information today. Taiwan&#8217;s Ministry of Defense says the aircraft carrier Shandong, which joined China&#8217;s military in 2019, was heading north...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China&#8217;s aircraft carrier Shandong was spotted in the Taiwan Strait. Shandong crossed the Taiwan Strait on Saturday. At that time there were two other ships with it. The Ministry of Defense of Taiwan announced this information today.</p>
<p>Taiwan&#8217;s Ministry of Defense says the aircraft carrier Shandong, which joined China&#8217;s military in 2019, was heading north through the Taiwan Strait on Saturday afternoon. At that time it was on the border between the two countries.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Defense said that the passage of the Chinese aircraft carrier with two ships through the Taiwan Strait is closely monitored and they have responded appropriately.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Defense of China was contacted to inquire about the matter, but there was no response. There was no mention of it on the social media channels of China&#8217;s armed forces.</p>
<p>The aircraft carrier Shandong also took part in China&#8217;s military exercises around Taiwan last month.</p>
<p>Earlier in March last year, the Shandong crossed the Taiwan Strait a few hours before the talks between the President of China and the United States.</p>
<p>China has recently increased military activity around Taiwan. The self-governing island of Taiwan has also objected to this. However, Beijing considers Taiwan to be an integral part of China.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://secure.sbam.org/chinese-aircraft-carrier-in-the-taiwan-strait/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can Erdoğan vote with the support of Sinan Ogan?</title>
		<link>https://secure.sbam.org/can-erdogan-vote-with-the-support-of-sinan-ogan/</link>
					<comments>https://secure.sbam.org/can-erdogan-vote-with-the-support-of-sinan-ogan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tetreamra]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 17:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://secure.sbam.org/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The second round of voting in Turkey&#8217;s presidential election is tomorrow. This vote may determine whether Recep Tayyip Erdoğan, who is ahead in the first round of voting, or Kemal Kilicdarolu, the leader of the main opposition party, comes to power. However, the fate of these two leaders is now largely in the hands of...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The second round of voting in Turkey&#8217;s presidential election is tomorrow. This vote may determine whether Recep Tayyip Erdoğan, who is ahead in the first round of voting, or Kemal Kilicdarolu, the leader of the main opposition party, comes to power. However, the fate of these two leaders is now largely in the hands of Sinan Ogan and the ATA Alliance that supported him.</p>



<p>Sinan Ogan was not a well-known face before the first round of voting on May 14. He stood in the presidential election with the support of the ATA Alliance. The coalition is led by right-wing leader Umit Ozdag&#8217;s Victory Party. Sinan Ogan of the nationalist genre got 5.2 percent of the votes in the first round. He was third in terms of getting more votes.</p>



<p>No one received the 50 percent needed to become president in the first round. Erdogan came closest to winning with 49.5 percent of the vote. Next was Kilicdarolu. His vote was 44.8 percent. As a result, if Sinan or the ATA coalition behind him gets the support, the presidency will be almost certain for Erdogan and Kilicdarolu.</p>



<p>Many analysts say that a candidate named Muharram Inse withdrew from the election a few days before the first round of voting. Many of his supporters voted for Ogan. In addition, there are many young voters in Turkey who do not like Erdogan or Kilicdarolu. They also voted for Ogan and ATA alliance.</p>



<p>Sinan Ogan&#8217;s supporters can be divided into three groups. Some of them may vote for Erdoğan. Another part will vote in favor of Kilicdarolu. And some supporters don&#8217;t go to vote at all<br />Mesut Yezen, Professor of Sociology, Sehir University<br />According to Mesut Yezen, a professor of sociology at Istanbul&#8217;s Sehir University, there is a segment of the electorate in Turkey that does not want to see Erdogan as president. They have no interest in today&#8217;s mainstream political parties in the country. Many of these voters also have secular attitudes. As a result, they are opposed to the religiously conservative politics of Erdoğan and his coalition People&#8217;s Alliance.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Kemal Kilicdarolu has the support of pro-Kurdish political party People&#8217;s Democratic Party. They also have a close relationship. Professor Mesut Yezen said that part of the Turkish voters is also upset with the People&#8217;s Democratic Party. As a result they will not want to vote for Kilichdarolu.</p>



<p>Sinan Ogan is an international relations expert. He entered the Turkish Parliament in 2011 for the Nationalist Movement Party (MHP). He ran for president in the 2015 election. But did not succeed. Ogan was away from politics since then. After making an agreement with Umit Ozdag of the Victory Party, he again entered the political field as a presidential candidate.</p>



<p>On the other hand, Umit Ozdag is a professor of international relations. He was once the deputy head of the Nationalist Movement Party. Later got the same post in IYI party. The IYI Party is currently in Kilicdarolu&#8217;s coalition. After being expelled from the party, he formed the Victory Party in 2021. This group has gained a lot of support due to its nationalist activities.</p>



<p>Radical nationalist platform<br />Political analyst and author Etienne Mahkoupian believes that Sinan Ogan did not have much voter support before this year&#8217;s elections in Turkey. According to him, people voted for Ogan only after the support of ATA Alliance led by Ozdag. And if he didn&#8217;t get him, Ozdag might have chosen someone else as the presidential candidate.</p>



<p>Etienne Mahkoupian told Al-Jazeera that if Ogan had stood alone, he would have had the support of a handful of nationalist political and academic groups. He was supported by the voters of Ozdag and his party Victory Party.</p>



<p>Both Sinan Ogan and Umit Özdag opposed Erdogan and his party, the Development Party (AK Party), during the campaign before this year&#8217;s election. But suddenly on May 22, Ogan said that he would support Erdogan in the second round of voting. As a result, the ATA Alliance led by the Victory Party of Ozdag broke up on the same day.</p>



<p>Sinan Ogan held a press conference about this. Voters who supported him in the first round of the election urged them to vote for Erdoğan in the second round. He said that he has taken this decision to maintain stability in the country. However, Erdoğan did not make any promise to him in return.</p>



<p>Ozdag opposed Ogan&#8217;s decision. He said that the decision taken by Ogan is his own. Two days later, Ozdag held a joint press conference with Kemal Kilicdarolu. They signed a memorandum of understanding. In the memorandum of understanding, they agreed on issues such as the return of refugees from Turkey and curbing corruption, nepotism and terrorism.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://secure.sbam.org/can-erdogan-vote-with-the-support-of-sinan-ogan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
